BATTUR TUGSGEREL

tbattur22@yahoo.com | (314) 682-9660 | 22 Saline Ln, Fenton, MO, USA

PROFILE

Full-Stack Developer with over 15 years of hands-on experience in variety of technologies across all web application layers - frontend/backend and data storage.

Enjoy coming up with elegant solutions, stick to DRY/SOLID principles and follow common Design Patterns. Committed to lifelong learning, consistently enhancing my skills with the latest web development technologies and practices.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Material-UI, Tailwind CSS
- Backend: PHP/Laravel, Elixir/Phoenix, Node.js, Java, REST APIs, GraphQL
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis
- DevOps & Tools: Docker, Git, GCP, VS Code, Linux shell script
- Others: Web Services, Yii Framework, Drupal CMS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer

Achievers Solutions Inc. | Toronto, ON, Canada | Sep 2020 - Jun 2024

- Developed frontend applications with React (JavaScript/TypeScript), Redux and Material-UI for modern UI/UX.
- Built and optimized backend services using PHP, MySQL, Docker, and GCP.
- Designed and implemented REST APIs, ensuring efficient data flow between frontend and backend.

Full-Stack Developer

TemboSocial Inc. | Toronto, ON, Canada | Feb 2015 - Sep 2020

- Created and maintained single-page applications with React, Redux and Material-UI

- Developed backend services using LAMP stack, building REST API endpoints for seamless integration.
- Improved database performance with optimized queries and indexing.

Full-Stack Developer (Contract)

TD Bank | Toronto, ON, Canada | Jul 2014 - Jan 2015

- Developed interactive web applications with AngularJS for frontend and Java/Spring Framework for backend.
- Designed and integrated RESTful APIs to connect frontend and backend services.

Web Developer / Software Engineer

The Learning Machine Ltd. | Tamworth, UK | Mar 2010 - Jun 2014

- Built dynamic web applications using PHP (Yii framework), JavaScript, and MySQL.
- Created custom Drupal 6 & 7 modules and optimized existing web features.
- Worked with LAMP stack, AngularJS, Node.js, and jQuery Mobile to enhance UX.

Software Developer

Embassy of Japan in Mongolia | Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia | Aug 2003 - Aug 2008

- Developed multiple web and desktop applications using Java, PHP, and Visual FoxPro.
- Key projects:
- Visa Applicant Blacklist System A client/server application for tracking applicants.
- Web-based Content Management System Managed bilingual website content for the embassy.
- Project Management System Tracked and managed grassroots projects.

EDUCATION

MSc in Computer Science (Distinction) | 2008 – 2009

University of Birmingham, United Kingdom

- Software Engineering, Databases, Operating Systems
- MSc Project: Developed a Web-based Adaptive Learning Management System (J2EE, JSF, JSP, Servlet, PostgreSQL)
- Research presented at the 10th IEEE International Conference on Advanced Learning Technologies

CERTIFICATIONS

- MongoDB for Node.js Developers MongoDB University (2013)
- Information Technology Professional (FE) Certificate ITPEC, Mongolia (2007)
- Microsoft Certified Solution Developer (MCSD) IPC Testing Centre, Mongolia (2003)

LANGUAGES & INTERESTS

- Languages: English, Japanese, Russian, Mongolian
- Hobbies: Table Tennis, Chess